MARS
(火星)
(Metallic Rouge)
《金属口红》
Where's Malik?
马利克呢
He is resting from a cold.
感冒正在休息
It doesn't seem to be a good year.
今年环境似乎不太好
Oh my.
真受不了
Can I take a look inside?
我可以看看里面吗
Rouge, please.
露琼 麻烦你了
Okay.
我拉
Who did you say caught a cold?
你说谁感冒了
Isn't that Malik down there?
倒在那里的人不就是马利克吗
Malik.
马利克…
Malik!
马利克
What happened? You died from a cold.
怎么会这样 居然因为感冒而死去
What are you joking about?
你开什么玩笑
Alright, I'm being serious.
讨厌啦 我很认真的
Who are you?
你是什么人
Who am I?
我是谁呢
Rouge.
露琼
Please take this.
这个就麻烦你了
Okay.
啊 好的
Don't get in the way.
别挡路
Sorry.
啊 不好意思
Sorry, she's still a newbie.
抱歉 她还是个新人
Alright, Rouge. Don't be in a daze.
好了 露琼 别发呆
Look, Sarah is doing it again.
你看 莎拉的老毛病又犯了
Is it really okay that she picked up such a kid?
捡回那种孩子真的不要紧吗
What?
咦
Well…
那个…
Here you are.
给你
Thank you.
啊 谢谢你
Hey, Scar Head, hurry to clean up.
喂 疤脸 还不快点收拾
As Nean, how dare you slack off!
身为涅安还敢偷懒啊
Sorry.
抱歉
See you tomorrow.
明天见了
Good night, Rouge.
晚安 露琼
Good night, Miss Sarah.
莎拉小姐 您也晚安
Is yours missing?
不见了吗
I remember it's here this morning.
我记得今天早上还在这里的…
You can use mine.
用我的吧
No way.
不可以
You'll stop functioning,
你会停止运转
and then you'll be scrapped.
这样的话 会被报废的
Newbie, goodbye.
新人 再见了
You too. If you don't get Nectar today…
你也是 要是今天不施打涅克托的话…
It's okay. I must have put it somewhere.
没事的 一定在某个地方
Hmm.
嗯
Good job.
辛苦了
Who is the boyfriend of our celebrity?
我们招牌明星的对象是谁啊
A big shot at Panakea Corporation.
万灵企业的大人物
It seems she's found a great sponsor.
看来找到了不错的赞助者
Here's to Sarah Fitzgerald, the Canal Club's popular singer,
敬运河俱乐部的当红歌手
the lady who sustains our livelihood,
向支持我们生计的 莎拉・费兹杰罗女士干杯
Right, where's Kevin?
对了 凯文呢
Did something good happen to him?
是发生什么好事了吗
Look at this.
你们看
Nectar can be sold at a good price.
涅克托可以卖到好价钱
I heard if it's injected into one's body, one can experience the extreme pleasure.
毕竟听说注入人体内的话 就能体会到有如升天的快感
If others pick a fight with you, I'm not going to help you.
要是被找碴我可不管哦
Those guys have Asimov Code in their bodies,
那些家伙体内有阿兹莫夫代码
so they won't resist us humans.
无法反抗我们人类的
Hey.
喂
Do you know about the possibility of Nean being an alien spy?
你知道涅安 有可能是外星人间谍的这件事吗
Are you talking about Visitor?
那个来访者的吗
Do you believe that?
你相信这种话啊
What do you think? Beep.
你觉得如何哔
I don't think she is.
我想…她应该不是
Tell me your basis.
说说看你的根据
Well…
这个嘛…
I just have this feeling.
只是有这种感觉…
That's baseless.
空口无凭
What about the man she is with?
跟她在一起的那个大叔呢
He's an executive at Panakea Corporation, named Herman…
是万灵企业的高层 我记得是叫赫尔曼…
Herman Heyward?
赫尔曼・霍华德吗
That's him.
就是他
Although I've been watching them,
虽然我一直盯着
I didn't see the Nectar syringe.
但是都没看到涅克托注射器
You wouldn't be able to tell if you did.
就算看到了也看不出来啊
Aren't you the same?
你不也是一样吗
That's true.
也是啦
Beep beep.
哔哔
I need you to stay close to Sarah and find the evidence,
你要再跟紧莎拉 找到证据
then you can take action, beep.
然后才能采取行动哔
I'll meet you at the back of the theater at noon tomorrow, beep.
明天中午 在剧场后面等你 哔
For what?
做什么
For regular contact.
定时联络
Oh.
哦…
Do you get it?
你有自觉吗
Maybe.
应该有吧
Got it.
收到
What's wrong?
怎么了
Are you alright?
没事吧
Red Gladiator.
红色斗士…
Sarah.
莎拉
Do you get hurt?
你没受伤吧
It hurts.
好痛…
Are you okay?
你还好吗
This is the footage from the scene of a suburban homicide provided by some citizen.
这是匿名市民所提供的 一起郊区凶杀案的现场画面
BREAKING NEWS However, interference signal appeared
(新闻快报) (神秘的红色怪客肆虐) 但画面上这名疑似嫌犯的人物 周围似乎有某种噪声
I think…
我认为…
-What a problem. -it must be some radio interference.
-真是麻烦 -应该是某种电波干扰所引起的…
Right, I think it's the same guy.
对 我想应该是同一个人
Exactly.
没错
Exactly, that guy also appeared here.
没错 那家伙也出现在这里
BREAKING NEWS MYSTERIOUS RED FIGURE GOES ON RAMPAGE
(新闻快报) (神秘的红色怪客肆虐)
The flower sender didn't leave a name.
上面没有属名
I see.
这样啊
Give it back to me.
还给我…
Please give Nectar back to me.
请把涅克托…还给我…
I don't know.
我不知道啦
What are you talking about?
你到底在说什么
I'm begging you. Please.
求求你…我拜托你…
This is also a social reality.
这也是社会现实面呢
Sorry for the wait.
久等了
Well, who are you?
那个…你是哪位
Beep beep.
哔哔
You're the person inside the bird?
啊 是小鸟里面的人
I can't believe there's someone inside the bird.
想不到小鸟里面居然有人啊
What?
什么
Ah.
啊
Nothing, just can't believe there's someone inside the bird.
没有啦 想不到小鸟里面居然有人啊
just can't believe there's someone inside the bird.
想不到小鸟里…
Hey, is your memory damaged?
喂 你内存是坏了吗
Well, who are you?
那个…姐姐你是什么人啊
My name is Naomi Orthmann.
我叫直美・奥德曼
Nice to meet you. I'm here to support you.
很高兴认识你 我是来负责支援你的
Well, I am…
那个 我是…
I know who you are.
我知道
Thank you.
谢谢
Excuse me.
不好意思
I'd like a large fried rice, double-fried pork, mapo tofu and two bowls of fried sauce noodles.
我要大份炒饭 回锅肉 麻婆豆腐 跟两碗炸酱面
By the way,
对了
what about that bird?
那只小鸟呢
It is dead.
往生了
Well, I'm so sorry for your loss.
啊 这…还请节哀顺变
Thank you.
谢谢你
Has anything happened since then?
从那之后有什么进展吗
Well…
啊…
I still don't think Sarah is Viola.
我还是觉得莎拉不是拜欧拉
It couldn't be her.
不会是她
I'm sorry to tell you
很遗憾我得告诉你
Sarah Fitzgerald has been injecting Nectar.
莎拉・费兹杰罗有在注射涅克托
She's Nean.
她是涅安
And chances are she's one of the Immortal Nine,
而且十之八九 她就是不朽九人中的其中一位
Viola Keane,
拜欧拉・基恩
also known as…
又称…
Purgatory Viola.
炼狱的拜欧拉
(Episode 1: Crimson Is the Sound of Dawn)
(1 红奏于拂晓之时)
Please confess your guilt.
坦承自己的罪行吧
Don't do so.
别这样
I wouldn't want to see you again if I could.
要是可以 我根本不想再见到你
You're so indifferent.
真是冷淡
You have to keep your promise.
你要遵守约定
Of course.
当然了
But there was an accident.
不过 出了一点意外
I have given you all the information you need.
我应该把必要情报都给你了
Right, exactly.
没错 正是如此
You tarnished your beautiful body…
你不惜玷污自己那美丽的身驱
No. You offered your body to get that information.
不… 是奉献了自己的身体 才得到了那些情报
But all the Nectar were taken away, and I am so ashamed.
结果涅克托却全部被人所夺 实在是无脸见人
I'm so sorry for you.
真是替你感到遗憾
But this has nothing to do with me.
但这跟我无关
It was the red guy who took the stuff.
抢走东西的 是那个红色家伙
Right.
没错
The one who killed Nius and Achillus, the enemy of us Alters,
就是杀了纽斯与阿基里斯 我们奥塔的仇敌
that red Gladiator.
那名红色斗士
He also appeared here.
他也出现在我这里
What? You're lucky to be safe.
什么 真亏你能平安无事
You have to keep your promise.
你要遵守约定
I feel sorry for you.
我很同情你
After all, once you complete this job, you will be done with us Alters,
毕竟只要完成了这一票 你就能跟我们"奥塔"一刀两断
but unfortunately, it's all in vain.
想不到结果竟是一场空
Giallon.
迦隆
Silvia suspected you're the one who leaked our information.
希尔维雅怀疑 是你将我们的情报泄漏出去
What?
她吗
I gave Silvia my full assurance that you are innocent.
我有向希尔维雅大力保证过 说你是清白的
I almost got killed.
我也差点被杀了耶
That's the point.
就是这一点
I want to protect you, even though I have to disobey the organization.
我就算违抗组织也想要保护你
Has anything suspicious happened lately?
最近有发生什么不对劲的事吗
Like some stranger approaching you.
比如说有什么陌生人接近你之类的
You'll have to strike first.
先下手为强哦
Aren't you going to eat?
你不吃吗
I'll just eat this.
这个就好
What?
咦
This is a restored footage of the suspect from last night's murder scene.
这是将昨晚凶杀现场影像 尽可能消除噪声后的嫌犯画面
Who is he?
他是谁
You'll know when you see it.
看了不就知道了吗
I don't remember.
我没印象
Alright.
没问题
I think I know what's going on.
我大概知道是怎么回事
The suspect is said to have a similar body shape to the suspect who's seen at the murder scene
据传 该嫌犯与出现在著名涅安学者 罗伊・容格哈特博士凶杀现场
of Dr. Roy Junghardt, a well-known Nean scholar.
被人所目击的嫌疑犯 有着相似的身形
Alright. Have a piece of meat.
好了好了 吃块肉吧
I'll just eat this.
这个就好
Well…
那个…
Tonight, could you stay with me?
今晚…能陪陪我吗
I came here over the bridge.
我是过了这座桥来到这里的
I left all my old real self behind on the other side of the bridge
将过去真正的自己 全都舍弃在桥的另一端
to become a new one.
成为一个全新的自己
What is the real self?
真正的自己…是什么呢
Viola Keane.
拜欧拉・基恩
I used to like you.
我本来很喜欢你的
Nean cannot kill humans.
涅安是无法杀人的
We are not bound by rules.
我们是规格外的存在
You are the same as us, right?
你也跟我们是一样的吧
Weird.
奇怪
Am I wrong?
不是她吗
Are you Giallon?
你…是迦隆吗
I can't believe I am wrong.
我居然猜错了
I thought it was her.
还以为肯定是她呢
I forgot you have the ability to mimic.
我都忘记你还有拟态能力了
The one who attacked me at that time…
那个时候袭击我的人…
Yes, it was me.
没错 就是我
Hell Giallon.
黄泉的迦隆
Is it him?
就是他吗
Oh no.
糟了…
Why did you attack me?
为何要袭击我
I did it for your own good.
我是为你好啊
I wanted to give you a push.
想说来推你一把
How could I bear to kill you?
我怎么会舍得杀你呢
I wouldn't kill you.
点到为止
I really am gentle.
我真是温柔
You've been hesitating.
谁叫你一直犹豫不决
Can you really kill that lovely girl?
你真有办法 动手杀了那个可爱女孩吗
I can.
我下得了手
I doubt it.
我很怀疑
That's why I'll do it for you.
所以我才会代替你…
Rouge is not that red guy.
露琼不是那个红色家伙
She has nothing to do with this.
那孩子跟这件事毫无关系
Is that so? She knows your name.
是这样吗 她可是知道你的名字哦
Viola.
拜欧拉
I think she's an agent of the Aletheia and working for them.
我想她应该是真理部的特务 也就是他们的手下
Killing her is just right, don't you think?
解决她刚好而已不是吗
I didn't expect that.
这我倒是没料到呢
This is really interesting.
哎呀 还真是有趣
But I have to take my leave now.
不过我要先行告退了
You said you can kill her.
你刚刚说过"下得了手"
Then you're the star.
那么接下来 你就是主角了
Come on, it's your show time.
来吧 好戏上场
Take her down,
你就尽情歌唱
and sing as long as you want.
直到打倒那个家伙为止吧
Farewell, Viola.
那么再见了 拜欧拉
Tell me your name before I kill you.
在我杀了你之前 告诉我你的名字
Metal Rouge.
钢铁…露琼
I am one of the Immortal Nine,
我是不朽九人之一
Purgatory Viola.
名为炼狱的拜欧拉
You are good.
有一套
Don't dodge.
躲得开吗
Naomi.
直美
Let her make a few more moves, and I can do the analysis.
再让她多出招几次 就能完成分析了
Why did you kill Nius and Achillus?
为何要杀死纽斯和阿基里斯
Why are you targeting us?
为什么要盯上我们
Who exactly are you?
你到底是何方神圣
She had part of her arm ion accelerated.
利用离子将腕部进行加速
And her arm is also equipped with a high-frequency vibrating blade.
腕部上还有高周波振动刀刃
I just want to sing.
我只是想要歌唱
I just want to be happy.
只是想要得到幸福而已
What's wrong with that?
这样有什么不对
Aren't you done, Naomi?
还没好吗 直美
I've sent it.
传送过去了
Don't be that arrogant.
别太嚣张
Tell me,
告诉我
what's the difference between us and humans?
我们和人类到底那里不一样
I will not die.
我要活着
I want to survive.
我要活下去
Exceed the pressure resistance limit.
超越耐压极限
The armor is about to melt away.
甲壳外皮要融解了
This is the end.
这样就结束了
The first time I met you was on a rainy day like this.
第一次遇见你 也是在这样的下雨天
Where are we going next?
接下来要去哪里
It's been decided.
已经决定好了